GEOFFREY M. CRITTENDEN

WEB DEVELOPER / SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CHICAGO, IL I (312) 485-6300 I geoffcritt@gmail.com I GitHub: GeoffCrittenden

I am a former Naval Officer and combat-seasoned aviator who has recently transitioned to software development. I have over a decade of experience in leadership, management, planning, analysis, teaching and execution. I am currently seeking opportunities to grow into a full-fledged software engineer. My goal is to work for a company that will allow me to use my strengths and experiences to contribute immediately while I progress as a software developer.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, SQL, ActiveRecord, HTML, CSS, Rspec, TDD, Object-Oriented Design, Git, Leadership, Planning, Decision-Making, Communication

RECENT SOFTWARE PROJECTS

CityPulse.io I Source

 Visualizing data from eight APIs to display a current snapshot of activity across Chicago using many technologies (Ruby on Rails, Javascript, PostgreSQL, WebSockets, Redis, Pusher, APIs, TwitterStream, & Heroku).

shUR.Ly I Source

 A URL shortener built with Ruby, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, and Base64, deployed to Heroku.

Instant Meal Ordering | Source

 Framework for a fast-food ordering mobile app to expedite the point-of-sale for restaurants, built with Ruby, Sinatra, Javascript, Ajax, HTML5 & CSS.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Dev Bootcamp | Chicago, IL | 2013

- Nine-week intensive software training program centered on developing web applications with a primary focus on Ruby on Rails.
- Particular attention was given to pair programming, group projects, and agile workflow.

M.S. - Digital Cinema | DePaul University | 2012

· Completely digital film & TV production focusing on the independent filmmaking model.

B.S. - Atmospheric, Oceanic & Space Sciences | University of Michigan | 2000

- Completed College of Engineering Core Curriculum.
- Concentrated in atmospheric technology, space systems design and orbital mechanics.

PREVIOUS PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Media Production Professional I IMDb Profile I 2009 - 2013

 Worked for numerous film, TV and web productions in multiple roles, including Producer, Production Manager, Camera Operator, Location Manager & Production Assistant.

Defense Contractor I BroadBay Group, Inc. I 2008 - 2009

- Operated airborne camera and provided aviation support for military units in training.
- Created an air-to-surface video streaming platform, utilizing RF and IP technologies, for clients to receive real-time video from in-progress operations.
- Co-authored Naval Special Warfare (SEALs) unmanned aircraft systems operating instruction.

Naval Officer / Combat Aviator / Flight Instructor | U.S. Navy | 2000 - 2008

• Over eight years of experience in leadership, management, instruction, learning, planning, analysis and execution.